We sigh whenever we're about to come to a standstill
Owarinaki tabi no tochuu tachidomarisouna toki
While moving on this endless journey.
Fukai tameiki kobosu bokura wa
Everytime we lunge for it, it escapes and flies off.
Tsukamikaketewa mata hanareteitta
But now, there's nothing to be afraid of
Demo ima wa mou nanimo osoreru koto wa nai
The powerful ties that bind our hearts
Kokoro wo tsunagu tsuyoi kizuna wa
Will never come loose.
Keshite hodoke wa shinai sa
After a lifetime of searching, we finally arrived
Sagashitsuzukete tadoritsuita
Here, where the period lies.
Kono basho de piriodo ni
Let's change all our sorrow and rage to power.
Kanashimi ikari chikara ni kaete
Destiny is right within our reach.
Unmei wa sugu soba ni
Along with the recovered Lan Fan,
Ed engages in combat with the Homunculus Pride.
He works out a plan while his mettle is tested,
and successfully retrieves Al.
But Pride swallows Gluttony, a comrade of his,
and obtains his abilities.
Elsewhere, Mustang has reunited with Hawkeye and his men.
They've kidnapped the Führer President's wife in order to hold her hostage.
Filial Affection
Wake up, Al.
Hey, Al!
Can you hear me?
Alphonse!
This scent...
Edward Elric.
I'm sure Hohenheim will have no choice but to show himself if I were to capture you.
Ed!
Young master!
Sorry,
it's Greed now.
You scum...
Give young master back his body!
No can do.
Here he comes!
Are you okay?!
I don't need your help!
Shut up!
Your arm hasn't even fully recovered yet, right?!
So what?!
Just worry about yourself for now.
I'm going to need your help later, you know.
Keep going!
Sorry, I couldn't finish him.
Heh, don't worry about it.
I can't blame you for not being able to beat him.
Even from my perspective, he's a monster.
Wake up!
Alphonse!
Huh?
Dad?
Yo.
So...
If you're here...
Am I in Kanama?
Yup.
Why am I...
Since when...
I remember now! Pride!
Dad, the Homunculus Pride is inside me!
Yeah, I heard everything from Mr. Gorrilius.
It's Darius.
Drats...
It felt so disgusting. It was as if he was interfering with my soul.
They're like the alter ego of my alter ego.
Since you're my son, it's probably easier for them to interfere with your soul through the blood seal.
Old Man Fu!
Please treat his injuries.
How are things going over there?
Are you Edward's father?
Yeah.
The shadowy monster devoured Gluttony, and we hardly stand a chance.
Greed and Edward are fighting him, but things aren't looking too good.
It's all my fault...
Everyone's in danger because I was captured by Pride...
There's an unlimited source of light due to the fire, and I've already used up all of my flash bangs.
We can't use that same trick again.
This isn't good.
At this rate, the people living in the slums will be dragged into it as well.
Dad.
You're a skilled alchemist, right?
Of course.
You'd be amazed.
There's something I'd like to ask of you, considering your skill.
Well then...
The view is pretty clear now.
No use in taking cover.
You can't escape from my nose.
Dammit...!
Hey, you alive?!
More or less...
Should you really be worrying about others right now, Greed?
I wonder how much more you can take at this point.
You monster.
A rather rude way to address your sibling, don't you think?
Mind if I eat you?
Eat me and you'll have a stomachache, Big Bro.
Oh? Finally decided to show yourself?
Hohenheim.
Heroes are supposed to show up late.
Heroes?
So you think you're able to defeat me?
Nah, that's impossible.
You're pretty scary, after all.
What is he planning?
Is he aiming for something?
He's coming!
Wow, what a disappointing strategy.
You just don't know when to give up!
Al!
So he came back, just to be taken hostage again?
Your son is quite the odd one.
Don't you dare...
...to make fun of my son.
Hohenheim!!!
Amazing...!
He actually sealed him in.
What's the big idea?!
You got Al stuck in there too!
What the hell were you thinking?!
It wasn't my idea.
It was Al's.
It worked!
You can't use your ability in here.
Is that really a cause for celebration?
You can't escape either.
If you crack open an exit to leave even for an instant...
...I'll use my shadow and-
I don't have the slightest intention of getting out of here.
Why don't we engage in a test of wills, Selim?
No, Homunculus Pride.
My body doesn't require oxygen, light, or even food.
You're going to quietly sit here with me for the entire day,
until the Promised Day comes to an end.
Defeating Pride in his current state would be difficult.
And if we were to let him run loose,
it would cause massive damage to the surroundings.
That's why Al offered to use himself as a decoy to trap him without engaging in combat.
With this, we've gained some time to work out a plan.
But you guys didn't even discuss it with me-
He said,
"If I were to tell Brother, he'd definitely be against it."
He did the best he could to think of a way that would keep everyone alive.
Don't get mad at him.
Okay, let's start with putting this fire out.
Al!
Brother!
Sorry for doing this just after we were reunited.
But I had to, because I was the one who caused this mess.
And besides, I only have to be in here for a day.
I'll be fine, Brother.
Lust is gone, Envy is gone, and Gluttony now, too.
Wrath is at the the joint exercise in the east,
and Pride can't move right now.
The only ones left at Central right now are Father and Sloth.
Greed! What the hell are you thinking?!
Told you earlier, didn't I?
I'm going to become the king of the world.
Don't you think there's been a lot of Ishbalans in Central lately?
Yeah, man.
I heard there's a group of them near the abandoned building to the west.
Speaking of Ishbalans...
Remember the lad with the cross-shaped scar who used to live here?
I wonder how he's doing.
Yo, speak of the devil!
We were just talking about you!
I'm looking for a slum by the name of Kanama.
Kanama is located on the edge of town,
in the forest to the south.
I see. Thanks.
Oh yeah, isn't the little girl with you?
You know, the one who was
carrying around a black and white cat.
She actually came back here a little while ago.
What?!
She didn't go back to her country?
What is she up to?
You guys finally did it!
What are you talking about?
You guys were the ones behind it, right?
The ones who blew up Bradley in his train in the east.
Blew up?!
Huh? Was I wrong?
This is news to us.
Well, I figured you teamed up
with the other Ishbalans and did it.
Well, everyone was saying that
they were going to commit terrorism.
They didn't gather here to do such a thing.
They're good friends of ours who seek to change this country in a method other than terrorism.
I should stop being so enthusiastic about my work.
Because of that, I've soiled my new suit.
The real performance starts after daybreak.
It's useless.
There's no way my dad would make it so easy for a child to be able to break through.
This is what happens when you make fun of humans so much.
You guys don't know anything about us.
You shouldn't think that everything will go your way.
Same with that scheme.
From my perspective, it's just careless planning.
Careless?
That's right.
You call us human sacrifices,
and it seems as though you're planning on using us to accomplish something...
What if we were to escape outside the country for the fear of our own safety?
At that point, your plan would have been completely ruined.
As you say, there are humans who believe that their safety comes first.
However...
Yes, for example, Wrath's wife.
There once was a time when I was about to be hit by a car in town.
She tried to save me, ready to sacrifice her own life.
Though she doesn't know I'm a homunculus,
I was completely taken aback by her desperate action.
I've always had a father, but never a mother.
That's why, to be honest, her existence was fascinating.
I began to wonder whether that's what having a mother was like.
Wrath's wife...
Madam Bradley, right?
That's right.
I can't believe how low you are to deceive such a kind soul...
You're right. It was  as if we were playing a game of house.
But it was fun living with her,
and I do love her.
Then-
There are...
There are humans, like Wrath's wife, who would throw away their own life to protect something dear to them.
And those of you who were chosen to be human sacrifices,
possess a strong heart, even out of those people.
There's no way you'd throw away this country and flee.
For instance, you came back here to fight.
There's not a hint of carelessness in our plan.
Colonel.
It's almost time.
Right.
Let's go, Lieutenant.
What in the name of...
What happened here?
And what is this mound?
Well, if it isn't Jerso and Zampano!
Darius!
D-Don't tell me Kimblee sent you here to eliminate us?
Huh?
What are you, high?
I stopped working for Kimblee months ago.
You're just saying that to get us off guard, and then you're planning to kill us!
I'm not!
I can't trust you!
Heinkel's probably hiding somewhere over there, ready to ambush us.
Quit being so insistent, idiot!
Doctor Marcoh!
What did you just call me?!
You want to fight, Porky Pig?!
Edward.
That's Zampano!
You-
So Scar was with you guys.
What are you saying?!
The gorilla said it!
Sorry to rush you when you just arrived, but we should make arrangements asap-
Hey!
Why can't pigs, fatties and gorillas learn to get along?!
Are you picking a fight, punk?!
Oh, so you guys really did stop working for Kimblee.
If we kept working for him, he'd just dispose of us.
Definitely.
Well thanks to that, we're fugitives now,
but it does feel nice.
Yeah.
Also,
those guys definitely won't abandon us.
It'll finally begin once the sun comes up.
Yeah.
I hope we'll all live to see the next day.
Looks like they've come to terms.
Where did the old man run off to?
He went to go scout out the town.
Alone?
Yeah.
He said that it would end up being more convenient,
since he's the only one whose face hasn't been seen by the enemy.
He said he'd go and check up on a couple of things, such as Colonel Mustang's movements,
but for the most part, I think he's worried about the whereabouts of Lin.
Ah, makes sense.
Are you done making arrangements with Scar and them?
Yeah.
The plan has been decided.
I see.
So it's time at last.
Your brother is pretty gutsy.
He's trapped in there with that monster in pitch darkness, after all.
If it were me, I would have gone crazy by now.
Yeah.
Al's giving it his all.
Now, the rest...
...is up to us!
The Promised Day...
...is here!
The promise we never made
Kawashita hazu no nai yakasoku ga
yet again
Kyou mo
tries to snatch our future away from us.
Bokura no mirai wo ubaou to suru
Why is it that we can't rejoice
Hoshigatteita mono wo te ni shitemo
straight from the heart
Sunao ni
when we obtain something we've always been after?
Umaku waraenai nowa nazedarou
The overflowing tears aren't from feebleness or remorse.
Afureru namida wo yowasa ya koukai ja nai
They're fragments born from agony.
Itami ga unda kakera de
Of all the moments and destinies,
Donna shunkan datte unmei datte
I realized there's one absolute certainty.
Hitotsu dake tashika na mono ga aru to shitta
Even if things get tough and I'm at my limit
Genkai datte konnan datte
I refuse to give up.
Akirametakunaiyo
Please, don't let go.
Konomama hanasanaide
I can feel the warmth of your right hand
Kataku nigirishimeta kimi no migite no nukumori
where it's tightly joined with my left.
Koko ni arukara
Denny! Denny!
Hey, Denny!
Shut up...
What do you want?
You need to wake up!
Or else it'll begin!
What'll begin?
The solar eclipse!
Solar eclipse?
Geez... what time do you think it is?
It's way too early for the solar eclipse to begin.
H-Hey! Don't look at the sun with that!
You'll go blind!
I know that.
Come here, Brother!
There's smoke rising from town!
Don't leave the house today, got it?!
Cedi Squad in the western district reporting.
We've discovered Mustang and his men in District C75.
We're currently engaging.
However, they have the Führer President's wife as hostage,
and it's very difficult for us to attack...
I don't care. Attack.
Huh?
As long as Roy Mustang stays alive, it's fine.
The woman means nothing to us.
Have her killed along with Mustang's men.
Freeze!
Will you shoot?
Shoot everyone except for Colonel Mustang!
The peace-accustomed masses are oblivious to the crisis right before their eyes.
They can't even begin to imagine the destruction awaiting them.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 50, Upheaval in Central.
Upheavel in Central
The weak reel in loss, and the strong trample them down.
That is war.